<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<travels>
<title>The Site</title>
<flag>DobeStack_Left.gif</flag>
<flag_right>DobeStack_Right.gif</flag_right>
<headertext>
The building site consists of about 1.25 acres in the SW corner of the property. The site was laid out when the easement was created in 2006. At that time, a _LEFT_a href=_Q_http://test.co.jefferson.wa.us/weblinkext/DocView.aspx?id=384859_AND_dbid=1_Q__RIGHT_survey_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_ was done to provide the building site envelope, encompassing the existing house and barn.  We're free to do pretty much what we want in the building site, as long as we abide by county code.
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
When the survey was performed to define the easement, the concern was to ensure the use of the existing house and barn.  However, nobody seemed to have considered that the house and barn were unusable and needed to be rebuilt. Since our intent is to replace the existing 2-bedroom house in essentially the same location and replace the existing barn with a workshop and Auxiliary Dwelling Unit (ADU), we had to answer some questions before closing on the property. 

_LEFT_UL_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Is electricity available? Yes. At the road. According to the neighbor, service is reasonably reliable.
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Is phone/internet/TV available? Yes. Phone is at the road, and our cell phones have strong signals. High speed DSL is available. Satellite TV would be the television option.
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Is the property flood prone? No. The building zone is high enough above the creek that flooding is not a problem.
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Is fire danger high? Not really. The area gets enough rain year round that forest fire does not seem to be a high concern.
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Are there wetlands or endangered species? No. There are no wetlands or endangered species that would affect the building zone.
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Are there seismic or stability concerns? No more than anywhere else in Washington. The building site is level.
_LEFT_/UL_RIGHT_

With all those questions answered, we were left with three main issues:
_LEFT_UL_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Can a sufficient, acceptable water supply could be supplied?_LEFT_/LI_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Are the approximate existing house and barn locations buildable?_LEFT_/LI_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Is a substantial portion of the existing septic reusable and can it be expanded to the ADU?
_LEFT_/LI_RIGHT_
_LEFT_/UL_RIGHT_

_LEFT_H3_RIGHT_Water_LEFT_/H3_RIGHT_
_LEFT_P_RIGHT_
The real-estate offering presented "an established water right". The water right is, in actuality, a water claim. The water claim was filed during the establishment of the State's water claim registry in 1974. The water claim is for 4000 gph from two cisterns for agricultural, stock watering and domestic use. The claim states water use was continual since 1933. However, as an unadjudicated claim, the claim is just that, a claim on such water use.  The odds of upholding such a claim during an adjudication are dependent on historical evidence of continual use consistent with the statement of the claim.  Thus, upholding the claim would require documentation of the use for agriculture, stock watering and domestic use, without any intervening five year period of non-use, since 1933. The spring being the only water source for the house would probably be acceptable evidence of domestic use. The agricultural and stock watering claims would be difficult to document if ever seriously challenged. Indeed, since the establishment of the conservation easement prohibits agriculture or stock on most of the land, the water claim for such use is almost certainly void (or will become void in the next several years). 
_LEFT_/P_RIGHT_
_LEFT_P_RIGHT_
An uncertain water claim will require other alternatives. The other (probably only) alternative is a private well. Such a well can be constructed.Indeed, establishing a well producing under 5000 gpd is permit exempt, but it must comply with the requirements of the 
_LEFT_a href=_Q_http://www.wria17.org_Q__RIGHT_
Washington State Water Resource Inventory Area 17 (WRIA 17)_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_ rules. 
In the Tarboo Creek subbasin of WRIA 17, new watershed management rules are in effect January 1, 2010. Under the new rules:
_LEFT_/P_RIGHT_

_LEFT_UL_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_
a private well may only drilled if there is sufficient reserve capacity in the sub-basin. Because we will probably be the first well in under the new management rules, the reserve requirement shouldn't be an issue.
_LEFT_/LI_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_
a private well will be restricted to 500 gpd maximum, 350 gpd average use. Although any well producing under 5000 gpd is permit exempt, these limits will still be in effect.
_LEFT_/LI_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_
a water meter will be required on the well. Water usage must be reported yearly to verify compliance with the limits above
_LEFT_/LI_RIGHT_
_LEFT_/UL_RIGHT_
None of the new water rules impose unacceptable burdens. They do however seriously restrict water usage beyond previous levels. Being the first well put in under the new rules will almost certainly lead to additional bureaucratic burden and expense as the rules become known and established.

_LEFT_H3_RIGHT_Buildable Lot_LEFT_/H3_RIGHT_
The establishment of a building site is most closely tied to buffer and setback requirements of the county. The following setbacks are given in
_LEFT_a href=_Q_http://nt5.scbbs.com/cgi-bin/om_isapi.dll?clientID=355032279_AND_infobase=jeffco1.nfo_AND_softpage=PL_frame_Q__RIGHT_Jefferson County code_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_:

_LEFT_UL_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_
(18.30.050) Setback from Coyle Road: 20 feet
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_
(18.22.270) Buffer from fish bearing streams: 150 feet + 5 foot setback. May be reduced to 112.5 feet + 5 foot setback with habitat management plan (HMP).
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_
(18.22.270) Buffer from non-fish bearing streams: 75 feet + 5 foot setback. May be reduced to 56.25 feet + 5 foot setback with HMP.
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_
(18.15.150) Setback from commercial forest (CF-80): 250 feet
_LEFT_/UL_RIGHT_
Based on our own field measurements using a GPS and tape measure, we found the county GIS maps could not be relied on for guidance on the stream locations.  The bed of  east fork of Tarboo Creek is substantially different than that mapped on the GIS. In addition, a non-fish bearing stream shown east of the house does not exist; hence the non-fish bearing buffer appears to be a moot point. The field measurements do indicate however, that the house is only located approximately 90' from some portions of the fish bearing creek. The current barn location is probably mostly outside 155' from the creek, although  further measurements are needed to confirm this.  
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
Because of the proximity of the creek, a new structure cannot be build on the existing house site.  Moving the house west approximately 30 feet in order to avoid the stream buffer with a HMP will likely impinge on the existing septic tank (moving it 155 feet in order to to avoid the stream buffer without an HMP will impinge on the tank, d-box, and or drain field). An existing tree would  likely need to be removed. Moving the house 30 feet southwest would avoid the septic tank, but likely require the removal of two existing trees. Finally, aesthetically, the more the site is moved to the west, the less desirable the site becomes as the distance to the creek is increased. Moving southwest is even less desirable as the house is moved away from the creek and towards the road. 
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
Additional possibilities are to move the house site to the west side of the property, to move the house to the current location of the barn (outside of any stream buffer) and locate the ADU on the west side of the property, or to move one or both structures towards the road. These alternatives would require substantial change to the existing septic system, including conversion from a gravity to pumped system. The distance from the riparian zone and lower elevation would also substantially decrease the aesthetic qualities of the site. Moving structures near the road is considered aesthetically unacceptable.
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
Since we didn't like the alternatives, we decided to look into "reconstructing" the existing house, as allowed under 18.22.070 (6). But what does it mean to "reconstruct"? Initially, talking to general contractors, we believed reconstructing would mean saving at least a portion of a wall, something unlikely to occur since the existing house doesn't even have a foundation. However, after further clarification by the county, we found that the only restriction is that the new construction stay within the footprint of the existing house. We now believe that we will be able to build in the existing house location and it will be "reconstruction".
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_

The final requirement, to provide a setback of 250' from the CF-80 zoned state timberland south of Coyle Road, was initially thought troublesome. A setback of 250' feet would preclude building on any portion of the building zone approximately southeast of the current barn location. This is probably about 75% of the building zone. After further clarification by the county,  however, it seems setback can be administratively waived with a letter stating the impacts of forestry are understood. In addition, the 250' setback requirement is, or will soon be, a moot point. The 250' setback is because the parcel south of Coyle Road is zoned CF-80 (commercial forest). That parcel is proposed for inclusion in a Dabob (Tarboo) Bay Natural Resource Conservation Area (NRCA). NRCA lands do not require a buffer or setback. According to the Department of Natural Resources, the parcel will be transferred to the NRCA by June 2011.

_LEFT_H3_RIGHT_Septic System_LEFT_/H3_RIGHT_
The maintenance Evaluation of Existing Septic, a report required at sale of a property with a septic in Jefferson county, showed the existing 2 bedroom septic to be in acceptable condition. However, several points  were still of concern with regard to the feasibility for its use. 
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
The first concern involved the possible impact on the existing septic if the building site needs to be changed because of the setback issues described above. Almost any alternative building site would have a large impact on the existing septic either directly (impinging on it) or indirectly (requiring conversion to a pumped system). In addition, when the existing septic was established in the 1980s, an identified reserve field was not required. Any modification of the existing septic will require the septic be brought up to the current code with the establishment of a reserve field. Although there should be sufficient room for the reserve field, it does add risk (the ground may not perc) and cost. 
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
The second concern was that the addition of an ADU, even a 1 bedroom ADU, will require the expansion of the septic to a 4-bedroom system (county code requires 1-bdrm ADUs to be counted as 2-bdrm units). Indeed, as we found out, we cannot expand the existing septic because county code requirements on the drain line spacing have changed since the existing septic was installed. The ADU will need to be a separate septic. There should be sufficient land for this expansion and the resulting reserve field, but risk and cost are increased.
Test holes dug by the septic engineer confirmed the soil should be acceptable for a conventional septic system, either a gravity fed or pressure fed, sand line system.
</headertext>

</travels>
