<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<travels>
<title>The Property</title>
<flag>DobeStack_Left.gif</flag>
<flag_right>DobeStack_Right.gif</flag_right>
<headertext>
Things we know about the property:
_LEFT_UL_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_The house and barn were build in the 1920s_LEFT_/LI_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_There's a water right claim from 1975 claiming water use back to the 1930s_LEFT_/LI_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_The house was maintained at least until the 1990s_LEFT_/LI_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_The house was owned by a single owner from the 1970s to the 2000s_LEFT_/LI_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_The house was occupied by tenants for a while_LEFT_/LI_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_In 2006, the property has bought by a logger from Port Angeles. He logged the property, then sold the easement to JLT, then sold the property._LEFT_/LI_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_The previous owners were the first to own the property with the conservation easement._LEFT_/LI_RIGHT_
_LEFT_/UL_RIGHT_
</headertext>

<entry>
<text>
The property is just under 50 acres. It's 1/2 mile across. The southern border is Coyle Road. South of Coyle Road is state timberland that is being transferred into a newly formed Dabob/Tarboo Natural Resource Conservation Area.  That means the forest south of Coyle Road will be permanently protected. To the east and north of the property are several miles of additional state timberlands. These lands are susceptible to logging by the state. To the west is the only neighbor. Its a 100 acre property with horses, llamas, and an organic farm. The East Fork of Tarboo Creek and several tributaries run across the property. In the satellite photo you can see the remants of the logging roads. The building site with the existing house and barn are in the lower left corner.
</text>
<image>
images/Coyle_pictures/Property.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
The property was logged in 2006 and replanted, mostly with what I think are Douglas Fir. The new firs are about 5 feet tall. A lot of red alders are also sprouting up. They're mostly about 6 to 10 feet tall. The red alder will continue to grow faster than the firs for the forseeable future. The taller, older trees are near the springs, creeks and tributaries and on slopes where logging was restricted. From the high points of the property (the north edge), there are nice views of the Olympics to the west. Although we haven't seen any yet, the neighbor tells us coyote, cougar, deer and bear inhabit the area.
</text>
<image>
images/Coyle_pictures/SL_Coyle.jpg
</image>
</entry>


<entry>
<text>
The building site is in the southwest corner of the property, abutting the road. When the easement was created, the building site was designed to accomodate the existing house and barn. However, nobody seems to have considered that the house was a teardown, and current regulations won't allow building within 150' of the stream.  The current house is about 80' from the stream. Most of our due diligence when deciding to purchase the property was determining what we could rebuild where. Currently it appears we will be allowed to rebuild the house in the same footprint. The barn is also within the 150' setback but we won't be allowed to rebuild there, so any other structure will need to be moved a little to the west or south.
</text>
<image>
images/Coyle_pictures/smaller_land.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
The existing house is two bedroom, one bath, 1320 sq ft., from the 1920s. It sits above the creek at the east edge of the building site. Sometime in the last 10 years or so, it stopped being maintained. The roof is partially collapsed and there's severe water and mold damage throughout. At this point, its a teardown. There is electic service to the house, although its currently off. The water supply is a spring-fed gravity system. The spring originates on the hill in the conservation zone. Pipes carry the water down to the house, across the stream. There was a wood stove for heat, although it may have also had some sort of electric heat. There's an existing two-bedroom septic that was installed in the 1980s. The septic is still in good shape and can be reused.
</text>
<image>
images/Coyle_pictures/house1.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
The existing barn has also seen better days. I would really have liked to be able to save it, but there isn't that much to save. There's no foundation and some structural issues. Plus, its in the way of where we want to put a new structure. 
</text>
<image>
images/Coyle_pictures/barn.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
The East Fork of Tarboo Creek flows behind the house and barn. Salmon runs are starting to appear again.
</text>
<image>
images/Coyle_pictures/creek.jpg
</image>
</entry>

</travels>
