<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<travels>
<title>The Easement</title>
<flag>DobeStack_Left.gif</flag>
<flag_right>DobeStack_Right.gif</flag_right>
<headertext>
The property at 231 Coyle Road has a conservation easement on about 97% of its area. The easement means we own the property and have full access and legal control of it, however, we are restricted in the development and use of the conservation zone. In our case, 
_LEFT_a href=_Q_http://www.saveland.org/_Q__RIGHT_Jeffersion Land Trust_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_
(JLT) owns the easement.
JLT is a non-profit organization in Jefferson County, Washington, that protects natural resources by working with landowners to purchase development rights to properties, or purchase properties outright, to maintain land in a natural state and prevent future development of vulnerable habitats. For 231 Coyle Road, a previous owner sold the development rights of the property to JLT. When we purchased the property, we became bound by the conservation easement, which lasts in perpetuity.
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
The purpose of the conservation easement is to protect the Tarboo Creek watershed and restore salmon runs to historical patterns. The East Fork of Tarboo Creek and several small tributaries flow across the property, making it an important piece of the Tarboo Creek watershed 
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
The level of restriction on land use by a conservation easement is subject to negotiation between the original seller and purchaser of the easement. In this case, the original seller of the easement sold the entire property concurrent with the easement and therefore was willing to sell nearly all the development rights of the property. That reasoning combined with the importance of the watershed to JLT led to a fairly stringent conservation easement on the property.
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
The easement covers all the property outside of a surveyed building site. The building site contains the current house and barn. In the building site, we are free to do what we want. However, within the conservation zone, we are restricted. Generally, any activity detrimental to the conservation purpose of the easement is prohibited. Specifically, the easement prohibits:
_LEFT_UL_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Residential, agricultural, commercial or industrial development_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Building of any structures_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Operation of wheeled or motorized vehicles_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Storage of motor vehicles, trailers or equipment_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Livestock grazing_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Kenneling, penning or containment of animals_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Intentional introduction of non-native species_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Mining or extraction of resources_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Dumping or storage of material or waste_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Cutting, pruning or removal of trees or vegetation_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Withdrawal or diversion of water, except from the residential spring_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Damming or diking of any waterway_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Use of pesticides, herbicides or fertilizers_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_/UL_RIGHT_

Specifically allowed activities include:
_LEFT_UL_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Maintenance of the existing spring-fed water system to the building site_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Construction and maintenance of a well for use in the building site_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Maintenance of the portion of the existing septic system that impinges on the conservation zone_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Construction of a trail system for non-motorized use_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Construction of one bridge no more than 4 feet wide over the creek for non-motorized access_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Construction of three benches_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Emergency flood control measures if necessary_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Activities as required by the state or county for public health or safety_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Restoration of the habitat_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Sustainable harvest of one cord of wood per year of naturally downed or dead timber_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Hunting and fishing_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Selective, sustainable harvesting of timber in conjunction with a plan to restore a native old growth forest_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_LI_RIGHT_Sustainable harvesting of non-timber products (e.g. berries, mushrooms)_LEFT_/li_RIGHT_
_LEFT_/UL_RIGHT_
In short, we can build trails and benches and pick berries, but mostly its just sit back and watch the trees grow back to a native old growth forest, helping that happen when we can. Actually we can also hunt and fish, but I really don't see that happening!
</headertext>
</travels>
