<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<travels>
<title>Greece/Turkey '08</title>
<flag>Greece.png</flag>
<flag_right>Turkey.png</flag_right>
<headertext>
In April 2008, we took a 12-day Holland America cruise from 
    Venice to Croatia, Greece and Turkey. The itinerary included Split, Athens, 
    Istanbul, Mykonos, Santorini, Ephesus and Olympia. Jim and Mary met us for 
    the weekend in Venice before we left on the cruise. I've split the 
    additional pictures into separate galleries for 
    _LEFT_a href=_Q_gallery.php?destination=GreeceTurkey08_Venice_Q__RIGHT_Venice_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_, 
    _LEFT_a href=_Q_gallery.php?destination=GreeceTurkey08_Split_Q__RIGHT_Split_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_, 
    _LEFT_a href=_Q_gallery.php?destination=GreeceTurkey08_Athens_Q__RIGHT_Athens_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_, 
    _LEFT_a href=_Q_gallery.php?destination=GreeceTurkey08_Istanbul_Q__RIGHT_Istanbul_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_, 
    _LEFT_a href=_Q_gallery.php?destination=GreeceTurkey08_Ephesus_Q__RIGHT_Ephesus_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_,
    _LEFT_a href=_Q_gallery.php?destination=GreeceTurkey08_Mykonos_Q__RIGHT_Mykonos_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_, 
    _LEFT_a href=_Q_gallery.php?destination=GreeceTurkey08_Santorini_Q__RIGHT_Santorini_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_ and 
    _LEFT_a href=_Q_gallery.php?destination=GreeceTurkey08_Olympia_Q__RIGHT_Olympia_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_.
</headertext>
<entry>
<text>
We started out with a long weekend in Venice. Venice far 
        exceeded expectations. We were expected something  like Amsterdam, 
        but with more touristy canals. I didn't realize there really aren't cars 
        in Venice and that the boats are the only way to get around. We really 
        enjoyed wandering the streets. It was also good to see Jim and Mary for 
        the weekend.
</text>
<image>
images/GreeceTurkey08_Athens_gallery/GreeceTurkey2008_00015.jpg
</image>
</entry>
<entry>
<text>
We visited Split when we went to Croatia just a year 
        before. Our main goal this trip was to re-visit the pizza place we had lunch at 
        last time. It was still there and still really good. Has to be the 
        best pizza in Croatia. 
</text>
<image>
images/GreeceTurkey08_Athens_gallery/GreeceTurkey2008_00026.jpg
</image>
</entry>
<entry>
<text>
We met the Greek distributor of Steve's products in 
        Athens. He was kind enough to spend most of his day showing us Athens. 
        It was really great to have some local help as we rushed between the 
        sights. It was good to finally visit the Acropolis, having seen pictures 
        of it since childhood. It was actually higher than I thought.
</text>
<image>
images/GreeceTurkey08_Athens_gallery/GreeceTurkey2008_00040.jpg
</image>
</entry>
<entry>
<text>
Istanbul is a big modern city. We had time to see the 
        biggest sights, Blue Mosque (in the picture), Aya Sophia, and Grand Bazaar, as well as to 
        spend an evening in the newer pedestrian-only shopping/restaurant 
        section.
</text>
<image>
images/GreeceTurkey08_Istanbul_gallery/GreeceTurkey2008_00076.jpg
</image>
</entry>
<entry>
<text>
Mykonos is the party island. Mykonos Town is fairly 
        small with a lot of shops, restaurants and bars. We also took a bus out to one of 
        the beaches for a mid-afternoon snack. It was still slow season, but 
        there were plenty of people on the beach. I tried wading in the 
        water - COLD!
</text>
<image>
images/GreeceTurkey08_Mykonos_gallery/GreeceTurkey2008_00104.jpg
</image>
</entry>
<entry>
<text>
Ephesus was a city of 250,000 inhabitants at its peak in 
        the Roman period. Its roots go back much further, to before Alexander 
        the Great. (This is also where Paul preached to the Ephesians - I always 
        wondered who the Ephesians were). By the middle ages, Ephesus was 
        abandoned and lost. It was uncovered in the 19th century and now is 
        undergoing excavation. It's really interesting seeing a true Greco-Roman 
        site: many of the carved inscriptions were in Greek and a lot were in 
        Latin, a 2500 year old bi-lingual city.
</text>
<image>
images/GreeceTurkey08_Ephesus_gallery/GreeceTurkey2008_00177.jpg
</image>
</entry>
<entry>
<text>
I had high expectations for Santorini, and the island 
        exceeded them. We walked up to Fira from the water instead of taking the 
        donkeys or cable-car. We also took a bus out to Oia. It was even 
        prettier than Fira. 
</text>
<image>
images/GreeceTurkey08_Santorini_gallery/GreeceTurkey2008_00208.jpg
</image>
</entry>
<entry>
<text>
Olympia was our last stop. These are also Greco-Roman 
        ruins, but seemed mostly Greek. The stadium is the best preserved part 
        of the site. The original start and finish lines still exist for the 
        stadium races. The pieced together east and west facades of the Temple 
        of Zeus are in the adjoining museum. They're really impressive.
</text>
<image>
images/GreeceTurkey08_Olympia_gallery/GreeceTurkey2008_00273.jpg
</image>
</entry>
</travels>
