<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<travels>
<title>Kenya/Tanzania '17</title>
<flag>Kenya.png</flag>
<flag_right>Tanzania.png</flag_right>
<headertext>
In June 2017, we joined Olga, Charlie, Jim, Joelle, Tony, Amy, Nancy, Nik, Doug, Cleo, Carl, Dawn and Kathy for a safari in Tanzania through Overseas Adventure Travel. Before joining the group, we spend three nights in Nairobi, Kenya.
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
In Nairobi, we visited the Giraffe Center, David Sheldrick Elephant Orphanage and Nairobi National Park. 
_LEFT_BR_RIGHT_
After flying to Kilimanjaro and joining the safari, we visited Terengire and Serengeti National Parks as well as the Ngorongroro Crater conservation area. We had three guides during our time in Tanzania: Godliving, Nas and Emmanuel. The guides were extraordinary and the quantity and accessibility of the wildlife far exceeded expectations. In addition to the wildlife, we visiting a Maasai family, an Albino support organization, a local school and took the the local bus (the 'dala dala') to a village market.

<!--
Additional pictures are split into separate galleries for 
    _LEFT_a href=_Q_gallery.php?destination=KenyaTanzania17_Elephants_Q__RIGHT_Elephants_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_, 
    _LEFT_a href=_Q_gallery.php?destination=KenyaTanzania17_Lions_Q__RIGHT_Lions_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_, 
    _LEFT_a href=_Q_gallery.php?destination=KenyaTanzania17_Zebras_Q__RIGHT_Zebras_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_, 
    _LEFT_a href=_Q_gallery.php?destination=KenyaTanzania17_Antelopes_Q__RIGHT_Antelopes_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_, 
    _LEFT_a href=_Q_gallery.php?destination=KenyaTanzania17_Hippos_Q__RIGHT_Hippos_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_,
    _LEFT_a href=_Q_gallery.php?destination=KenyaTanzania17_Buffalo_Q__RIGHT_Buffalo_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_, 
    _LEFT_a href=_Q_gallery.php?destination=KenyaTanzania17_Rhinos_Q__RIGHT_Rhinos_LEFT_/a_RIGHT_ and 
-->
</headertext>
<entry>
<text>
Elephants were common in both Tangire and Serengeti. We saw many of them quite close up. In Serengeti, one herd numbered about 60. While staying at the tented camp in Serengeti, we watched as a herd of 10 elephants drank all the water from the camp water tank. When they finished, they knocked the tanks over so the little ones could get any water left. The camp staff tried to throw rocks and make noise to move them away from the water, but elephants do pretty much what they want.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN0387.jpg
</image>
</entry>
<entry>
<text>
We saw numerous lions. They also were quite easy to spot near the road. In Serengeti, we watched one lion from about 15' away as it devoured a freshly killed zebra. In Ngorongoro, a lion used our vehicle for shade and as a blind as it hunted zebras. We could have reached out the window and petted it. Many of the lions we saw were either in trees or on top of rock formations called kopjes.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN1322.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
Rhinos are the only one of the 'big five' that we didn't get really close to. We saw rhinos in both Nairobi and Ngorongoro but we were quite a distance away in both cases. 
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN0176.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
We were lucky to see several leopards in Serengeti. In one case, we watched the leopard come down from a tree to hunt. After a while, we heard a squeal which the guide told us was a gazelle getting killed. Indeed a few minutes later we watched as the leopard carried his dinner back into a tree. In another case we watched a leopard stalking gazelles for about 45 minutes until hyenas showed up and messed up the leopard's plans.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN0873.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
Cape buffalo were common in Serengeti. They were usually found in large herds. Sometimes you'd see a solitary male. The buffalo can be quite aggressive. If distrubed while in a herd, they can attack en masse. If you come across a solitary one, it can be even more dangerous: they get very aggressive when isolated. They just have a mean look when they stare at you.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN0189.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
Cheetahs can be difficult to see however we were really lucky. Shortly after getting to Serengeti we came across a mother cheetah and her two cubs sleeping no more than 20' away from the road in the grass.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN0681.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
Serval cats are quite difficult to see since they are strictly noctural, but we found one out and about during the day. Even our guide was excited to see the serval cat. He said in his ten years of being a guide he'd only seen the serval cat three times.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN0845.jpg
</image>
</entry>


<entry>
<text>
Zebras were all over the place in large herds. We joked about how you can tell new visitors to the parks: they're taking photos of zebras. After the first couple hours, you've seen seemingly thousands of zebras. No more photos.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN0877.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
Wildebeests, aka gnus, are also very common in the parks. There's a herd of 1.5 million of them in Serengeti. Due to the early start of the dry season, we missed the huge migration, but there were still plenty of stragglers around.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN0224.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
Most of the fresh water pools seemed to have hippos in them. When the weather was overcast, the hippos also commonly seemed to be out of the water. Hippos are really fun to watch. They seem to be forever pushing each other around and fighting amonst themselves.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN0747.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
Ostriches were also quite common in both Terengire and Serengeti. They tend to stand in open plains, so they are easy to spot.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN0202.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
Although not very large, I thought impalas won the prize for most beautiful on the Serengeti. They are very common and very stately with their sleek bodies and curved horns.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN0248.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
You can easily find mongoose on termite mounds. They dig into the mounds and eat the termites. Unlike Hawaii, they belong in Africa. They also eat snakes.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN0336.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
Warthogs don't when any prize for beauty, but they are still fun to watch. They are common and often intermix with the other animals
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN0352.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
Topi are antelopes we commonly saw. They're one of the bigger species of antelopes in the national parks.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN1128.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
Dik-dik are cute, tiny antelope, usually about 8 pounds, the size of a house cat. Although common, it wasn't that easy to get a good picture. They tend to run when you get close.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN1172.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
We came across quite a few large troupes of baboons. They're quite fun to watch, especially when they have babies. The locals don't have a very high opinion of the baboons. The baboons can be quite troublesome, getting into things and stealing food. They're not shy about trying to steal food during picnics.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN0455.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
Although skittish, hyenas were also commonly seen, usually lurking a couple hundred yards away. When staying in the tented camp in Serengeti, we were warned not to leave any shoes outside the tents because the hyenas steal them.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN0715.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
Jackals are also pretty common but difficult to get a picture of. They seem to be skittish around people. In Ngorongoro we watched as a jackal chased an eagle. At first we thought it was trying to grab the eagle. But jackals are scavengers, it was really trying to take away a catch the eagle had. It did succeed on getting it's meal away from the eagle.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN1403.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
The rock hyrax is found scampering around on the kopjes. They aren't rodents, they're mammals. Although quite small, the hyraxes are a relative of the elephant.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN1113.jpg
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
The African fisher eagle looks a lot like the American bald eagle.
</text>
<image>
images/KenyaTanzania17_gallery/DSCN0952.jpg
</image>
</entry>

</travels>
