<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<travels>
<title>4335 Thackeray</title>
<flag>DobeStack_Left.gif</flag>
<flag_right>DobeStack_Right.gif</flag_right>
<headertext>
4335 Thackeray is our house in Seattle. Build in 1910, it's 2+ bdrm, 1 3/4 bath. The basement was finished in the 70s or 80s. We've owned it since 1997. In general I really like the house.  The only downside I really see in the layout is that it doesn't have a bathroom on the main floor. There's one bath up and a 3/4 bath was added in the basement when it was finished.
</headertext>
<entry>
<text>
The house isn't quite a classic craftsman, it doesn't seem to have any particular style. I like the simple gable roof (although it does have a dormer on the south). It isn't quite symmetric with the door on the north and a bay window from the living room next to it. I'm not positive, but I think the bay window must have been an early addition (maybe 40s?)
</text>
<image>
images/4335Thackeray_pictures/DSCN0275.JPG
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
The next major exterior change I'd want to make on the house is to re-side. The asbestos siding is great for low-maintenance, but really should be swapped out. I'd change it to clapboard, maybe cement fiberboard (and add insulation to the walls - currently I don't think the walls are insulated).
</text>
<image>
images/4335Thackeray_pictures/DSCN0277.JPG
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
We have a small detached garage. My one absolute requirement when we were looking for a house was "no attached garage". I don't like garage doors. If you have to have them...carriage doors.
</text>
<image>
images/4335Thackeray_pictures/DSCN0276.JPG
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
The back of the house has the similar gable shape. There is a pop-out breakfast nook added in the 90s. I like the level of trim on the windows.
</text>
<image>
images/4335Thackeray_pictures/DSCN0278.JPG
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
This is the bay window in the living room (not a very good picture). Although difficult to see in this picture, the trim on the window is very odd which is why I think it was an addition (or possibly just an original mistake). The windows have been replaced and upgraded to double pane, but we replicated the leaded glass pattern. The left and right windows were originally casements, but we changed them to double hung (partly because the house has settled so much the windows are way off-square and the casements didn't work very well anymore).
</text>
<image>
images/4335Thackeray_pictures/DSCN0265.JPG
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
The south side of the living room has a fireplace with two windows. There are build-in seats on each side of the fireplace -- all details I like, although the painted brick of the fireplace is not my favorite material.
</text>
<image>
images/4335Thackeray_pictures/DSCN0266.JPG
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
Built in bookshelves frame the dining room. It doesn't quite show in this picture, but the center of the bookshelves, the dining room light and window don't quite all line up -- a symmetry issue that I've always though odd.
</text>
<image>
images/4335Thackeray_pictures/DSCN0267.JPG
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
There's a nice built-in hutch in the dining room. I like the way built-ins are used as wood accents.
</text>
<image>
images/4335Thackeray_pictures/DSCN0270.JPG
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
We've just finished updating our kitchen. The cabinets stayed (installed in the early 90s). We swapped out the vinyl floor and put in new appliances and countertops. The countertops are quartz, which is a material I like. My only concern is that we remodeled to the "granite/stainless steel" look at what is probably already near the end of its popularity, so our kitchen will look dated quickly.
</text>
<image>
images/4335Thackeray_pictures/DSCN0268.JPG
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
The breakfast nook was an addition from the 90s. I like the way it has lots of windows looking out into the garden.
</text>
<image>
images/4335Thackeray_pictures/DSCN0269.JPG
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
The main bedroom has one big double hung window looking out over the road. Upstairs, all the rooms have picture rails, where there are none downstairs. The picture rails do make a nice way to split the paint color between the walls and the ceiling, but I could do with or without them.
</text>
<image>
images/4335Thackeray_pictures/DSCN0271.JPG
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
The second bedroom we use more as an office. The double hung here looks over the backyard.
</text>
<image>
images/4335Thackeray_pictures/DSCN0272.JPG
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
In 2001 we had the bathroom gutted and redone. The original footprint was 5x8. We found a little extra space, but its still pretty limited. I really like how it came out. The wainscot and pedestal sink, white below, a darker, bolder color above look very classic. The floor is a simple white tile with black checks.
</text>
<image>
images/4335Thackeray_pictures/DSCN0273.JPG
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
We did a Corian surround for the shower which has worked really well.
</text>
<image>
images/4335Thackeray_pictures/DSCN0274.JPG
</image>
</entry>

<entry>
<text>
There's a large, cedar back deck. I'd probably do Trex or similar at Coyle.
</text>
<image>
images/4335Thackeray_pictures/DSCN0279.JPG
</image>
</entry>
</travels>
